한글자막 D (13myowncut@gmail.com)
다들 보고 있는 거야?
Are you watching this?
Look at this.
우리보다 숀 펜이
인질 문제에 더 적극적이야
Sean Penn is doing more about
the hostages than we are.
가여운 것들
우리 딸내미 또래인데
These poor kids...
they're like Catherine's age.
제가 연루됐다면 끔찍했을 거예요
인질범이었다 해도요
I'd be terrible in a hostage
situation, even as a hostage taker.
해병기지 방문과 관련해
국방부 장관 측 반응은 어떤지요?
So, ma'am, no word yet
from the Secretary of Defense
about joining him
at the Marine base?
아, 매덕스는 묵묵부답이더군
Uh, no, nothing from Maddox,
그치만 백악관 내에선
내가 더 먹어주는 걸 알게야
but he knows I've got a bigger
role in the White House now,
내가 바로 대물이니
지가 알아서 빨아야지, 뭐
which means I've got a bigger
dick, which means he can suck it.
흐뭇할 따름이야
연설문은 어찌 돼 가?
I'm so happy about that.
How's my speech coming?
조금 바뀌었습니다
사소한 부분예요
Oh, one minor change.
Just one word, really.
'신중한 대응'이란 표현을
'엄중한 대응'으로 고쳤습니다
"Considered response" is now
gonna be "robust response."
엄중이라?
제길, 멋들어지는군
Robust?
Damn, that's good.
대통령에 대한 충성심이
은연중에 묻어난단 말이지
Yeah, I mean, it's subtle
enough to seem loyal to POTUS.
- D.C.에서 찌릿찌릿해 하겠지
- 전기통닭구이 감이죠
- That's gonna electrify DC.
- Oh, it's gonna AC DC.
'엄중'이라니 좋은 단어군요
Robust is a good word.
'허세' 같이 흔하지도 않고요
And you don't hear it often,
like bumptious.
이번 사태 해결 과정에서
부통령 님께 딱인 단어죠
Yeah, it's what you want
to hear in a hostage crisis.
엄중함 말입니다
허세 따위가 아니고
Robust, not bumptious.
마이크, 자네 생각은 어떤가?
Mike, what do you think?
What do you think about robust?
엄중함이요? 좋습니다
갑자기 와인이 당기는군요
Robust? I like it.
It makes me think of wine.
풍부한(robust) 느낌의
와인을 좋아하거든요
It's actually
how I like my reds.
와인도 빨대 꽂아 드시죠?
You like your reds through a
bendy straw, too, right, Mike?
도넛 가루 묻었네, 마이크
You got donut on you, Mike.
수, 감사 잘 다녀오고
Sue, good luck at the hearing.
- 잊지 말라고, 질질 끌어
- 알겠어
- Remember, Sue, be dull.
- I will.
약속하고 오셨나요?
오늘 일정 없는데요
Are you here for a meeting?
I'm not expecting anyone.
- 업무 대리입니다, 클리프라고
- 안녕하세요, 개리예요
- Sue, I'm your fill-in, Cliff.
- Cliff. Hey, I'm Gary.
옆 자리에서 근무하죠
부통령 님 깍듯이 보필하세요
I'm your neighbor.
Remember, take care of Selina, okay?
VP는 '대단히 귀중한 분'이란
뜻이니까요
VP stands
for "very precious."
- 알았죠?
- 알겠습니다
- Okay?
- Okay.
- 클리프
- 네
- Cliff.
- Yes.
빕플로피디아입니다
This is the Veeplopedia.
필요한 모든 게
담겨 있을 겁니다
It's everything
you'll ever need to know.
부록으로 '클리프노트'도
있으면 좋으련만
Wow. Hope it comes
with CliffsNotes.
말장난 좀 쳐 본 거예요
제 이름이 클리프라
That was a play on my name.
My name is Cliff.
그러지 마세요, 클리프
Don't do jokes, Cliff.
유머엔 흥미 없으니
당신도 꿈 깨요
I don't have a sense of humor
and neither should you.
좋은 아침입니다
Good morning.
완벽하게 멀쩡한 두 단어가
어째 이리도 거슬리는지
How do you make two perfectly pleasant words
so irritating?
불알 통계 없이는
오줌도 못 갈기는 분 아니신가
And here he is, the man
who can't take a leak
without polling his balls.
선홍색 파일 갖다 주게, 조나
Bring me my cerise-colored
binder, Jonah.
선홍색 말씀이십니까?
알겠습니다
Cerise?
Yes, sir.
부통령께서 오늘
해군기지를 방문한다지
The VP's base visit today.
국방부 장관이
이름값을 하는군
Secretary of Defense Maddox
is living up to his name.
돌았지 황소새끼 마냥
(mad + ox)
He's mad as an ox.
두 분 사이의 다툼은
제가 중재할 수 있습니다
I'm sure I can break up
any catfights when I get there.
부통령 님께선 인질 문제에
상당한 신경을 쏟고 계세요
The veep's more concerned
with the hostage situation.
Yeah, I was talking
to POTUS last night.
어제까지만 해도
대통령 님께서
조나만한 크기로 풀발기도
거뜬할 정도로 찬성이셨어
He had a pro-strike hawk
boner the size of Jonah.
And then you talked to him
about it this morning
그러던 차에 자네와
몇 마디 나누시고는
군사 작전이라면
기를 쓰고 반대하신다고
and he's suddenly
totally against the operation.
제 일이라는 게
여론의 동향을 살피는 겁니다
All I do is provide POTUS
with the polls.
- 가감 없는 수치로써
- 맙소사, 질색이야
- Cold numbers.
- God, I hate numbers.
이 세상엔 숫자 놀음 없이도
잘만 사는 인간들이 천지야
There's cultures that don't even have
any numbers and they do just fine.
벤, 지금 직책이 마뜩잖으심
물러나는 편이 어떠실는지요
Well, Ben, it seems like you're ill-suited
for your job and you should resign.
제가 드리고 싶은 말씀은
부통령 님께서도 군사 개입을
Ben's breakdown aside,
the VP feels we need
적극 지지하신단 점예요
a quick military strike here.
자네가 했던 뇌엽절제술만큼
칼같이 해치워야 한다고
Yeah, precise and surgical,
like your lobotomy, Kent.
- 선홍색 파일 대령입니다
- 아냐, 그건 '체리 레드'지
- The cerise binders, sir.
- No, that's cherry red.
- 선홍색
- 죄송합니다
- Cerise.
- I'm sorry, sir.
제가 색맹 기가
좀 있나 봅니다
I must have a very specific
form of color blindness.
전 매일 같이 이걸로
즉석 국수를 해 먹습니다
I cook these noodles every day.
오, '국수'론이다
Oh, the noodle analogy.
뿅 가실 거예요, 다들
You guys are gonna love this.
나가 보겠습니다
I will leave.
딱 800 와트로
가열해야 합니다
They need to be heated
at 800 watts
3분 하고도
35초 동안
for three minutes
and 35 seconds.
과했다간 말라 비틀어질 테고
Any more and they'll dry out.
모자라면 축축하게 늘어지죠
Any less and they will be
flaccid and damp
비에 젖은 여인네의
머리칼처럼
like a lady's hair in the rain.
- 난데없이 왜 '국수'론이죠?
- 내가 얘기하지
- Why are we talking about noodles?
- No, let me rephrase that.
왜 시발 국수 타령하고 지랄이야
Why the fuck are we talking
about noodles?
I'll tell you why.
Hostage crisis, noodles... same principle.
작금의 인질 사태와
즉석 국수는 같은 원리라고요
시기적절한 개입이 필요합니다
서두르면 그르쳐요
Both require precision timing,
neither should be rushed.
국민의 65% 이상이
인명 손실을 감수한
Inaction only becomes untenable
when more than 65% of Americans
군사 개입에 동의할 때까진
몸을 사리는 게 정답입니다
support intervention
even with casualties.
부통령 님께 그대로
보고하란 말씀이신가요?
So you'd like me to tell the vice
president we do nothing until then?
사태를 관망하는 것과
넋 놓고 있는 건 다르네
Waiting is not doing nothing.
난 국수를 위해서라면
기꺼이 기다림을 감내하지
I choose to wait for my noodles
갓 부화한 아기새처럼
침샘이 아무리 아우성을 쳐도
even though my salivary glands
are crying out to me
like newly hatched birds.
그치만 그만한 보람이
있고 말고, 왜냐면...
But they will thank me
because I waited until...
지금껏 그 밥 말아 쳐먹을
개소리의 시간을 맞췄던 게야?
You just timed out
that whole shit analogy
좆만한 땡 소리에?
for your little ding?
존나 어처구니가 없어서
That is fucking pathetic.
매덕스한테서
아무 소식 없었어?
Hey, have we heard
anything from Maddox?
내가 뜬다고 입에
총알 거품 물지 않던?
Is he spitting bullets 'cause
I'm showing up at the base?
- 아뇨, 전혀요
- 정말?
- Nothing. Nada.
- Really?
- 괜히 께름칙하죠?
- 진짜 께름칙하군
- It's eerie, right?
- It is eerie.
안녕, 닐리오
우린 도착했지롱
Hey, Neilio. We're in.
이따 보자고
See you in there, I guess.
그러세, 고맙네
Okay. Thanks.
부통령 똥꼬에
고개라도 조아릴 녀석이야
Probably got his head
stuck in her ass.
그럼요, 당연하죠
맙소사, 당연해
Yes, I do.
Oh, my gosh, yes.
장관 도착 전까지
5 분간 전세이십니다
Hey, ma'am, you've got five minutes
of veep time before Maddox arrives.
- Yeah.
- They're not saluting you.
- 그래
- 왜들 경례하지 않죠
실내에선 안 하는 법이야, 개리
They don't salute
indoors, Gary.
실내인걸 어쩌라고, 개리
They don't salute
indoors, Gary.
반갑네, 해병
- Good morning, Marine.
- Ma'am.
이라크에서 복무했다지?
You served in Iraq?
I see.
그렇담 그...
And were you anywhere near...
- 바그다드요
- 안바르
- Baghdad.
- Anbar.
- 안바르 쪽?
- 예
- ...Anbar?
- Yes.
안바르라니, 훌륭하군
Anbar, wonderful.
여긴 2사단 주둔지입니다
Ma'am, this base
houses Marine 2.
해병 2사단 주둔지라 아네만
I understand
that Marine 2 is here.
내가 발퀴레의 기행 을
즐겨 듣는 걸 아는가?
And did you know in the CD player
I've got "Ride of the Valkyries"?
지옥의 묵시록 도 좋지
"Apocalypse Now."
무거운 영화지만
굉장히 좋아한다고
That's one of my favorite films.
It's dark, but I like it.
해병들은 '데블 독'이란
별칭을 좋아합니다
- Marines like to be called Devil Dogs.
- Devil Dogs.
듣던 대로 여기는
'데블 독'들이 천지구먼
You are a bunch of Devil Dogs,
that's what I hear.
나도 데블 독과
살았던 적이 있네만
I was married to a Devil Dog,
but he wasn't a Marine.
전 남편은 해병은 아니고
저스트 데블이었어
He was more of a devil.
She's so funny.
짓궂으시죠
귀하의 노고에
감사드립니다
Thank you for your service.
- 반갑네, 해병
- 용모가 인상적입니다
- Good morning, Marine.
- He has a nice face.
- 용모가 인상적인 해병일세
- 고맙습니다
- You have a nice face.
- Thank you, ma'am.
자넨 어디서 복무했었나?
And where did
you serve, Marine?
사격 중지!
Cease fire!
이 정도의 병력만으로도
반경 25 야드를 커버합니다
These small arms have a max
effective range of 25 yards.
소총 말씀하시는 겁니다
Small arms means guns, ma'am.
세상에, 정말이냐?
티라노의 발톱이 아니고?
- Oh, really, Gary? Not T-rex hands?
- Okay.
Mr. Secretary,
would you like to try?
장관 님, 시범 보이시겠습니까?
아닐세, 훈련 사격으로
충분하네
No, I'm good.
I've fired a gun before.
큭
Okay.
- 적군을 상대로는 물론이고
- 오호우
- In anger, too, I might add.
- Oh, uh-oh.
부통령 님께서 한 번
나서 보시지요?
But why don't you give it
a try, Madam Vice President?
아, 나는...
Oh, I don't...
0.5 초만 시간을 주겠나?
Um, can you give me
just half a sec?
뭐야 샹?
What the fuck?
- 역화 될 수도 있어요
- 그럴 리 없습니다
- This could backfire.
- It's not gonna backfire.
말 그대로 역화 될 지
누가 아느냐고
The gun could literally backfire.
That's where the phrase comes from.
장관 코를 납작하게
만들어 주십시오
Ma'am, this could really
chap Maddox's ass, too.
오, 좋지
그럴까?
Oh, yeah, it
would, wouldn't it?
명중시키기가 얼마나
어려운데요
You could chip a veneer and I
don't really want that to happen.
알 게 뭐야
해 보는 거야
I don't care.
I'm going in.
자 모두들?
해치워 봅시다
You know what? Let's lock and load.
What do you say?
Yeah? Yeah.
내가 왔다, 칸예 웨스트윙
Here he is, Kanye West Wing.
램지 의원 님이시죠?
Congressman Ramsey, right?
아뇨, 클리프라고
수의 수 격이죠
No, I'm Cliff.
I'm Sue's Sue.
- 남자 버전 수라고나 할까
- 뭐라고요?
- I'm the boy named Sue.
- What?
클리프, 말장난 치지 말라면
치지 않는 겁니다
Cliff, when I said no jokes,
that wasn't a joke.
업무 능률 감사에 참석할 땐
지루한 답변이 최고입니다
Sue, Hessler's efficiency hearing,
you've got to keep it dull, okay?
'블라잡'을 시전하세요
블라 x 5
Give 'em a blah job.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
다 알아, 조나
귀에 딱지 앉게 들었다고
I know, Jonah.
That's what everyone's been saying.
질질 끌라더군
그것마저 지루하다만
Keep it dull, which
incidentally, is also dull.
부통령 님께 감사를 표합니다
I'd like to first of all
thank the vice president
업무 투명성 제고를 위해
기꺼이 협조해 주시고
for waiving executive privilege
in the interest of transparency
이 자리에 윌슨 씨가 참석할 수
있도록 배려해 주셨습니다
and allowing Miss Wilson to
join us today on the committee.
긴장한 것 같죠?
Do you think she's nervous?
뭐 하러 긴장을 해요?
Why would she be nervous?
이딴 걸 보는
사람이래 봐야
The only people
watching this are you
댁 아니면
정신병자들뿐일 텐데
and some guy in the hospital
with locked-in syndrome.
먼저, 활동비 지출을
따져 볼까 합니다
If I may, I'd like
to begin with percentages
특히나 국내외 항공 교통비
of your office budget
dedicated to international
- 명목의 지출 비율 말입니다
- 몹시 기다려지는군요
- and domestic transportation.
- My pulse is racing, sir.
여깄습니다, 부통령 님
Here you are,
Madam Vice President.
손가락을 여기 방아쇠 위에
올리고 그대로 당기십시오
Ensure you keep your finger
straight and off the trigger.
All right.
This is fun, isn't it?
좋았어, 흥미진진하구만?
한 말씀 올려도 되겠습니까
민간인 냄새 작렬이십니다
If you don't mind my saying, ma'am,
there speaketh a civilian.
좋을씨고
도라이 냄새를 풍겨주지
All right.
There speaketh a pricketh.
오우, 지저스 퍼킹 에그머니!
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ!
오홓!
Oh!
죄송들 합니다, 그저...
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I didn't...
그보다 더한 소리도 듣는
친구들이니 걱정 마십시오
These fellas have heard a
lot worse than that, ma'am.
- 폭격음 말입니다
- 그렇단 말이지?
- Tremendous shot, by the way.
- Really?
어땠나?
백악관 내 최고 아니겠나?
Oh, how about that?
Fastest gun in the West Wing.
잘들 봤지?
소감이 어때?
- - Did you see that? How about it?
Yes, ma'am.
다들 알다시피
대단히 귀한 분이 오셨다
As you know, we have a very
special guest here today.
사전에 연설 내용에 관해
조율했다면 좋았을 텐데요
It would have been nice to have been
consulted about your speech, ma'am.
제가 도움을 좀
드렸을 겁니다
I could have given you
some advice.
내 앞가림은 내가 하네만
I know what I'm doing, George.
이번 인질 사태로
미루어 짐작컨대
With this hostage situation,
좀 딸리시는 듯합니다만
I don't think you have
the intelligence.
군사 정보력 말씀입니다
As in intel, of course, ma'am.
진심인가?
Are you serious?
지금 내 자질에
의문을 품는 겐가?
Are you actually questioning
my qualifications, George?
우즈베키스탄 이웃
4 개국을 둘러싸고
There are just
some security issues
안보 문제가 발생했잖습니까
with the four countries
that neighbor Uzbekistan.
4 개국 맞나요?
5 개국이었던가?
Is it four or is it five?
아님 6 개국?
것도 아님 7?
Or is it six?
Or is it seven?
모르시는군요?
You don't know, do you?
5 개국이야
It's five.
우선, 조지 매덕스
국방부 장관 님을 모시겠다
So first, please welcome the
Secretary of Defense George Maddox.
묵힌 똥덩어리를
출산한 것 같아
I pulled that
straight out of my ass.
꿈에 그리던 순간이었습니다
You were born for that moment.
이오지마 같은 새끼
I know.
He's Iwo Jima.
마빡에 승리의 깃발을
꽂아주겠어
I'm planting a flag
right on his head.
이제 한 번
차근차근 짚어 봅시다
Now I'd like to work
on breaking down
부통령 님의 공무 및
the vice president's official
정치 활동에 관해서 말이죠
versus political
duties if we can.
업무 능률 현황에 대해
감사가 진행될 줄 알았습니다만
Sir, I was told that I'd be asked
questions about efficiency.
그에 관련한 사항은
좀체 다루지 않으시는군요
So far you have
barely asked me any.
업무 능률 감사가 어째
전혀 능률적이지 않습니다
Your efficiency hearing
isn't very efficient.
질문이 받고 싶으시다?
이번 부통령의
You want a question?
What can you tell me
콴티코 해병기지 방문에 대해
어떻게 보시나요?
about this visit to
the Marine base at Quantico?
국방부 장관도 모자라
부통령까지 의전 차량을 동원해서
The government sending two different
motorcades, the defense secretary's
한 군데를 공략하다뇨
and the VP's,
to the same location.
- 그야말로 능률적이지 않죠
- 오, 이런 심벌즈
- That doesn't seem very efficient.
- Oh, shit a shark.
질질 끌라고
그렇게나 일렀거늘
This is why I told her
to be dull.
미처 이런 상황에
대비하진 못했나 봅니다?
Do you not have measures
in place to prevent
정부의 인적 물적 자원의
낭비가 아니면 무엇이죠?
this kind of wasteful duplication
of government resources?
물론 체계를 갖췄습니다
뭐랄까...
Sir, we have a system
that I believe to be...
'엄중한' 체계를요
robust.
- 엄중하다고요?
- 그렇습니다
- Robust?
- Robust.
그렇담 현재의
보좌 체계는
And you don't think it's a sign
별다른 문제없이 잘
굴러간단 말입니까?
that your office
is poorly managed?
저희 보좌진은
꽤... 엄중합니다
Our management team
is... robust.
얼씨구, 이젠 거의
정신 질환자 급이군
Okay, now she just sounds
mentally ill.
자리를 지키셔야
하지 않을까요?
Don't you have somewhere
you're supposed to be?
원격 근무해요
I'm working remotely.
'오늘의 어휘집' 같은 거라도
갖고 계신가 봅니다
I'm guessing you have one of
those word a day calendars.
오늘자 어휘가 뭔지
감이 오는군요
And I know what the word
for today is.
'엄중하게' 말이죠
It's robust.
단어의 뜻까지 정의내려 줄
의향은 없으시고?
Would you like to give me
a definition as well?
보아하니 유머 감각 깨나
있다고 자부하시는군요
Well, I'm guessing that you think you
have a sense of humor, Mr. Hessler.
사실이 아닌데 말이죠
'오늘의 어휘집'도 마찬가지고요
Which you are wrong about,
as you are about the calendar.
그것이 바로 제가 내린
엄중한 정의랄까요
That is my definition
of robust.
여기 빡빡이들 모두
연설문 들으면 질질 쌀 거예요
My speech is a face-melter.
These buzz cuts are gonna flip.
네 것도 아니잖아
내 지문이 떡칠 된 원고라고
It's not your speech.
My fingerprints are all over that sucker.
뒷면에 찐득하게
손이나 닦는 거랑은 다르죠
They're sticky and they're
on the back, Mike.
꼭지가 도는 엄중함을
맛보게 될지어다
It's time to robust a nut
all over this place.
- 망할, 망했어
- 뭐라고?
- Oh, shit. We can't.
- What?
수가 엄중하단 표현을
세 번이나 입에 올렸대
Sue, she just used robust
three times at the hearing.
- 그럼 안 되는데
- 옘병할
- No, she didn't.
- Yeah. What the...?
겹치지 않도록
다른 말을 떠올려야 돼
Selina can't use that now.
We need another word.
유의어 뭐 없을까?
Just a synonym for robust.
뭐라고 말 좀 해봐
뭐라도, 제발!
Give me something.
Give me a word. Any word!
'공격적인'
Aggressive.
너무 공격적이잖아
No, that's too aggressive.
We don't want to say that.
- '단호하다'?
- '확고하다'!
- Okay, resolute.
- Determined.
- 그거나 그거나!
- 그럼 내 걸로 가
- That's the exact same thing as resolute.
- Then we'll use mine.
폭발적인, 효과적인, 대담한
생각나는 대로 말하는 거야
Explosive. Punchy. Fearless.
I'm just saying words.
- '강한'이다!
- '강한'? 가릿!
- Strong. Go with strong.
- Strong? Strong, got it.
개리, 부통령 님
귀 좀 빌려야겠어
Gary, I need the speech.
I need the vice president's ear.
네 귀는 어따 두고?
반 고흐야
Get your own ear, van Gogh.
Back off.
썩 물러나지 못해
Thank you.
감사합니다
뭐야, 징챠
- Thank you.
- What the hell?
대단히 반갑습니다, 여러분!
Good morning, Marines!
- 우라
- 우라!
- Oorah.
- Oorah!
기세들이 대단하셔
Oh, my goodness.
조국의 안녕을 위해
충성을 맹세한
We who have answered
the call to serve
모든 해병 여러분
아시리라 믿습니다
this great nation know this,
우리의 자유를 위협하는 자는
그 누구가 될지라도
that those who
challenge our freedoms
엄중한 대응을
피할 수 없다는 사실을요
can expect a robust response.
- 곧 엄중한 세례가 이어지겠군
- 엄중한 대응은 피하기로 했잖나?
- There goes the R-bomb.
- I thought we weren't doing robust.
신중히 관망하는 중 아녔나?
I thought we were
still on considered.
세계 최강의 군사력을
자랑하지 않겠습니까
We have the best military
in the world.
우리 사전에
두려움이란 없습니다
And we are not afraid.
- 저기, 마이크?
- 네
- Hey, Mike?
- Yes, ma'am.
워싱턴 뒷구멍을 향해
촉각을 곤두세우라고
Stick a thermometer
up Washington's ass.
아마 열기로
후끈 달아올랐을걸
See how much heat
I just created.
싸다구를 올려붙이신 격이죠
Parting the cheeks.
'엄중하다'는 내 표현이야
수가 가로챈 거라고
You know robust is my word.
She stole my word.
수는 대충 앉았다
오는 거 아니었어?
She was supposed
to be dull, Mike.
신문에 내 얼굴
실린 거 봤지?
And did you see that photo
of me in "Politico"?
완전히 변비 앓는
여자 같았어
My God, I look constipated.
- 전혀 아니십니다
- 집무실에서 봐
- No, you don't.
- Meet me in my office.
변비 같진 않으세요
그 정반대라면 모를까
You don't look constipated.
You look the opposite of it.
정반대가 도대체 뭔데?
What's the opposite
of constipated, Mike?
- 후련함이랄까요
- 아냐
- Relieved.
- No.
후련함이랑 변비는
정반대가 아니야
Relieved is not the opposite
of constipated, Mike.
전화 끊어, 멍충아
Hang up the phone, dummy.
- 부통령 님, 이거 보셨어요?
- 뭔데 그래?
- Hey, ma'am, you seen this yet?
- What is it?
포스트지입니다
Just the "Post."
'부통령의 여인
엄중하게 통하다'?
"VP sister act
robusting the moves"?
이것도 좀 보시죠
Ma'am, there's
also... yeah.
이건 또 뭐
해쳐먹을 거리야?
What in the living
fuck is this?
D.C.프레스지에 실린
워드 클라우드입니다
It's a word cloud from
this morning's "DC Press."
각 단어의 크기는
그 사용 빈도를 가리킵니다
The size of each word corresponds
to its total number of uses.
요즘 사람들은 더 이상
문장으로 말하지도 않는다냐?
Do people not use
sentences anymore?
제 말씀은... 부통령 님의
'엄중함'이 압도적이거든요
Well, I mean, your word...
I mean, robust is dominating.
그러니, 뭐
좋은 징조죠
So, you know, that's good.
수 크기 좀 봐
Look at the word Sue.
- 수도 한 건 했네요
- 그렇네요
- Sue made it.
- Sure. It's there, too.
설리나는 어딨어?
Well, where's the word Selina?
아, 그건...
Oh, it, um...
어딨냐면...
It's, uh...
분명히 봤었는데
I just saw it.
찾았다!
저깄네요
Ha! There.
There it is.
넘 콩알만 하잖아
Look how teeny tiny that is.
'박살'보다는 큰데요
It's bigger than collapse.
부통령 님을 지칭하는 단어는
네 개나 되니까 그렇겠죠
It's teeny tiny because
technically you have four names.
부, 통령, 설리나, 마이어
Vice President Selina Meyer.
저희는 입에 올리지 않는
별명도 있으시고요
Yeah, plus all the nicknames
that we don't talk about.
수 이름은 하나밖에 안 되잖아요
포카혼타스나 히틀러
I mean, Sue only has one name
like Pocahontas or Hitler.
- 모비, 빅풋처럼
- 수!
- Or Moby or Bigfoot.
- Hey, Sue!
- 수?
- 부르셨습니까?
- Sue!
- Yes, ma'am?
너 이런 샹
수도 아니면서
What?
You're not fucking Sue.
클리프라고 합니다
수의 업무 대리죠
I'm Cliff.
I'm filling in for Sue
6 일에 있을 감사 재출석
전까지 대신 맡아 봅니다
while she preps for her return
appearance on the sixth.
재출석이라고라?
She has a return appearance?
뭐 때문에
앙코르 감사까지 땡기지?
What does she need
an encore for?
앙코르 맞습죠
팝콘 챙겨서 구경들 하셔유
Yeah, it's an encore.
Start popping your popcorn.
- 그래, 잘 알았네
- 닥본'수'
- Okay, thank you very much.
- Must Sue TV.
그쯤 해두라고
고맙네
I said that's enough.
Thank you.
개리, 이만 신임 상원의원
취임 선서식 준비나 하세
Gary, we need to start prepping
for the whole senator
swearing-in thing.
- 물론입죠, 개리오케 타임!
- 암, 그렇고 말고
- Oh, yeah. It's Gary-oke time.
- Yes, it is.
의원 별로 각 카드에
멘트를 적어뒀어요
All right, I put together
one card for each senator.
부통령 님, 제게 좋은
아이디어가 있어서 말입니다
Actually, ma'am, I had some ideas
about some opportunities here.
각 의원들이 내세운
정치 공약에
I think it'd be a good idea
if we focus more
더욱 집중하는 편이
인사치레보다 나을 듯합니다
on each senator's particular policy
interests rather than small talk.
- 나쁘지 않은 것 같군
- 네?
- Yeah, I don't think that's a bad idea.
- What?
코트 걸어 두게
일리가 있어
Yeah, take the coat.
That makes sense to me.
내 생각에도...
어머, 수다!
I think that...
oh, there's Sue.
나가들 있어
수!
Okay, get away from me.
Sue!
수!
말고, 진짜 수 말야
Sue!
No, the real Sue.
부통령 님 귀에서 냉큼 떨어져
내 말 듣고 있지?
You stay away from her ear.
Do you hear me?
개리오케는 끝났어, 이 친구야
대니오케 시대라고
Gary-oke is done, my friend.
It's time for Danny-oke now.
- 대니오케?
- 종말을 고하라고, 짜샤
- Danny-oke?
- End of an era, buddy. End of an era.
수선 그만 떨어
무슨 유명 인사야
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm not famous.
끽해야 D.C. 근방에서 그렇지
Maybe only in DC.
응, 그럼
나랑 킴 카다시안
Oh, yeah,
me and Kim Kardashian.
이만 끊자
부통령 님?
Oh, I've got to go.
Bye, bye, bye. Ma'am?
- 편히 앉지 그래, 수?
- 아, 죄송합니다
- Why don't you take a seat, Sue?
- Oh, sorry, ma'am.
앉게나, 수
Sit down, Sue.
단단히 짚고 넘어가자고
All right, I've got
a bone to pick...
저에 대한 총애가
분노로 바뀌시게 생겼습니다
Ma'am, I know you really love me,
but now you're gonna hate me.
뭔데?
What?
매덕스 장관이
블룸버그지와 인터뷰 했습니다만
Sec Def Maddox just did an interview
with Bloomberg.
그런데?
Yeah?
향후 '공격적인' 대응을
펼칠 거라고 언급했습니다
He's now calling
for an aggressive response.
- '공격적'이란 말이지?
- 저도 막 접했습니다
- - Aggressive?
Yeah, I just got that, too.
공격적인 게 엄중함보다
한 수 위인 거야?
Does aggressive trump robust?
더 엄중한 격이죠
Well, it's robustier.
아냐, 엄중함이 바위라면
공격적인 건 종이 쪼가리지
No, robust is like a rock
and aggressive is like paper.
앗, 실수
종이가 바위를 감쌀 수 있는데
Oh, shoot, paper covers rock.
I forget about that.
- 벤한테서 문자 들어왔습니다
- 뭐라고 해?
- We just got a text from Ben.
- And? What's his word?
부통령-님-곧장-모셔-와-
존나-회의-쳐할-거임
His word is "get-the-vice-president-over-here
right-now-we're-having-a-fucking-meeting."
띄어쓰기 없이
옆줄로 이어서 왔습니다
It's all one word hyphenated.
다시 한 번
말씀해 주시겠습니까?
Remind me, you said what?
- 어떤 대응이라셨죠?
- 엄중하다고
- Your response needs to be what?
- Robust.
- 엄중이라, 그리고요?
- 공격적이랬지
- Robust. And you said?
- Aggressive.
- 사태 파악이 되십니까?
- 아니, 안 돼
- You see the problem?
- No, I don't.
말들이 정리가 안 됐잖습니까
They're different words.
그 말인즉슨
무슨 의미인고 하니
And saying different
words means what?
어긋났다는 뜻이죠
서로 바라보는...
It means we're not
on the same...
- 밥그릇이 다르다고?
- 면이 달라요
- Diet?
- Page.
난 자네가 밥그릇
타령 할 줄 알았지
Oh, I thought you were
gonna say diet, Ben.
- 태도 역시 심히 거슬리는군
- 답해줄 의무 없네만, 벤
- I don't like your tone.
- And I don't have to answer to you, Ben.
여기 계신 라라 크로프트 께도
그렇고
Or to Lara Croft here
for that matter.
모두 대통령 님을
위하자는 취지 아니겠습니까
Yeah, perhaps not, but we
all work for the president.
오즈의 마법사 는 또 어딨대?
Oh, where is the great
and powerful Oz, by the way?
대통령 님만 안 계셨다면
근무하기도 수월했겠죠
Listen, we all know the White
House would work so much better
그치만 계신 걸 어떡합니까
if there wasn't a president,
but there is.
고로 항시 그 분을
염두에 두고 일해야죠
So we work around that.
어쩌면 되는지 알려드리죠
And we do that by sticking
우라질 입을 맞추는 겁니다
to the same fucking words.
언제는 자네 할 일이
아니었던 겐가?
And it's your job
to coordinate that, maestro.
바로 그거죠, 정정 들어갑니다
앞으론 '계산된' 대응입니다
That's right. So from now on, the
words are calculated response.
계산이라니?
거참...
Calculated?
That sounds so...
- 계산적이죠?
- 기집년 같다고, 그 말이야
- Calculated?
- Pussy-ass, that's what I was gonna say.
대통령 님 어깨에
힘을 실어 드려야지
You've got to light a fire
under the president's butt.
전방으로 돌격하세
Let's get some action here.
총질 한 방 당기시더니
저격수라도 된 양 저러시네
She fires a gun one time and she
thinks she's Rommel in the desert.
물론이지
나도 한 사격 한다고
Yeah, let me tell you something.
I'm a good shot.
그러니 앞으론 말이야
뭐랄까, 그...
You know what?
I may even start... you know,
호주머니에 휴대하고 다닐까 봐
어떻게 생각하나?
whatever it's called... packing heat.
How about that?
그래만 보십쇼
총기 규제 지지 들어갑니다
When you do that, I'm gonna
start supporting gun control.
- 새 국수 거리가 있습니다
- 당최 무슨 소린가?
- I have news on the noodles.
- What's he talking about?
- 인질 건에 진전이 있겠습니다
- 이런 잔치 국수가...
- We can move on the hostages.
- Cock-a-noodle-doo.
이런, 키스해 줄까 봐
당장 뒤져도 안 할 거지만
Oh, my God. I'd kiss you right now,
but I'm never gonna do that.
서두르면 6 일이나 9 일께에
개시 가능합니다
Earliest we could go in would
be the sixth or the ninth.
이를수록 좋습니다
대통령 님 성미 아시잖아요
We got to go early.
You know POTUS.
생각할 시간이라도 드릴라치면
변덕 부리실 거라고요
If we give him enough time,
he's gonna change his mind.
지루증 도지실 게 뻔해요
He's gonna
procrasterbate forever.
- 부통령 님께서?
- 어? 그래
- Madam Vice President?
- Huh? Yeah.
흠, 1 초만 주겠어?
Um, just give me one second.
1 초면 돼
One second.
에이미, 사무실에 전화 걸어
Amy, call the office.
- 부통령 님 사무실입니다
- 부통령 걸었습니다
- Office of the Vice President.
- This is the vice president.
- 네, 맞습니다
- 아니, 내가 부통령인데
- Yes, it is.
- No, no, this is the vice president.
- 아, 죄송합니다
- 괜찮네
- Oh, okay. I'm sorry, ma'am.
- It's fine.
일정표 확인해 보고
6 일에 잡힌 스케줄
Look into my calendar and
tell me if there is anything
모조리다 취소
가능한가 보도록
on the sixth that is immovable.
확인 결과
조정 가능합니다
Uh, no, ma'am,
it all looks moveable.
수의 감사 재출석을 제외한
모두 취소할 수 있습니다
The only thing that can't move is Sue's
second hearing appearance on the sixth.
- 그게 6 일인가?
- 그렇습니다
- Oh, that's on the sixth?
- Yes, ma'am.
예약 녹화 해놓으셔요
아마도... 끊으셨군요
Set your DVR.
I'm thinking of... okay, you hung up.
여러분, 6 일이 좋겠군요
Well, gentlemen,
the sixth it's gonna be.
가여운 청년들을
고국으로 귀환시킵시다
Let's bring these kids home
as soon as possible.
얘기 끝난 겁니다?
So we're all agreed?
6 일이면, 악당들에게
쓴 맛을 안길 수 있겠군요
The sixth, it's gonna be a bad day
for the bad guys.
대통령 님 뵈러 갑시다
Let's go find POTUS.
단지 조금이라도
빠르다는 이유셨죠
Now you went with the sixth
because it's before the ninth?
- 물론이지
- 수의 재출석과는
- Yeah, of course.
- And Sue's return to the committee
- 아무 관련이 없고요?
- 내가 염려하는 것이라곤
- has nothing to do with it?
- You know what I'm interested in?
무고한 우리 국민들을
안전하게 귀향시키는 것뿐
Getting innocent Americans
home safe and sound, right?
6 일에 예정된 모든 스케줄
조정해 두게나
Move everything off
of the sixth for me.
- 비울 수 있댔지
- 잘 알겠습니다
- You can clear that.
- Absolutely, ma'am.
조정할 스케줄이라곤
신임 상원의원 선서식뿐이니까요
The only thing I need to move is
the senator swearing-in ceremony,
거뜬하겠습니다
so we're good.
뭐라고?
What?
신임 국회의원들
선서하는 거 있잖아요
The senator
swearing-in ceremony.
모조리 취소 가능하다지
않았던가?
You said that
everything was moveable.
그건 취소가 안 되는데
And that's not moveable.
취소 불가라고
That's immoveable.
그런 게 있을리가요
Surely nothing is immoveable.
에이미, 닭대가리 앉혀 놓고
중력에 대해 논하는 것 같아
Amy, this is like explaining
gravity to a chicken.
의원 선서식은 하늘이 두 쪽
나도 못 옮깁니다만
The senator swearing-in
ceremony is set in stone.
부통령 님이 상원 의장직을
겸하고 계시잖아요
She's the president
of the Senate.
반드시 부통령 님
주재 하에 열려야 합니다
She swears in
all newly elected senators.
알겠나? 이해가 돼?
똑똑히 알아 먹었냐고
Right? You get that?
You understand it?
- 구글링 해 볼래?
- 아뇨, 이해했습니다
- Do you need to Google it?
- No, ma'am, I understand.
그런 것 같아 뵈지 않는데
I don't think
you do understand.
쪼개고 있잖나
왜 쪼개는 건데?
Because you are grinning.
Why are you grinning?
- 그렇지 않습니다만
- 쪼개고 있어
- I'm not grinning.
- You are grinning.
존나 프랑스만한 크기의
대참사를 빚어냈어
You have made a fuckup
the size of France
근데도 시방 실실
쪼개고 있다고
and you are fucking
grinning about it.
애쓰고 있습니다만
저도 제 안면 근육이 왜 이러는지
I'm trying not to.
I'm not sure why my face is doing this.
오, 제기랄
- Oh, damn it.
- Okay.
속속들이 알지 못하지만
I don't know what's going on,
부통령 님 본의가
아니었을 거예요
but she didn't mean
what she just said, okay?
부통령 님, 혹시 도와드릴...
Okay.
Ma'am, is there anything...
- 기밀이야!
- 오, 하나님!
- Classified!
- Oh, my God!
내가 6 일로 밀어부쳤어
I pushed for the sixth, right?
내가 주도한 일정이라고, 에이미
I got my date.
This is my date, Amy.
내가 지휘한
인질 구조 작전인데
This is my hostage
rescue mission.
그 날 가장 주의할 점은
The most important
thing on the day
일과에 있어서
의심을 사선 안 된다는 점예요
is we can't look suspicious
in our movements.
응, 알고 있어
정상인인 척 잘 해
Yeah, I know that.
I know how to act normal, okay?
정상적일 거야
상정상일 거라고
I'll be normal.
It's gonna be great.
지금 내 입장이
믿기지가 않는다
I can't believe
I'm in this position.
이게 다 클리프 탓이야
쳐웃기만 하는 빨간 마스크 새끼
This is all Cliff's fault,
that grinning fucking Ewok.
다들 종합상황실에
가있을 텐데
They're all
in the situation room.
나만 존나 신삥 똥통에
쳐박히게 생겼다고
I'm stuck here swearing in
a shitload of senators.
바로 저기 원격 상황실이
마련돼 있으니까요
Well, the virtual sit room
is right back there
이미 접속되어 있으니
안정적으로
and we've got a secure
video teleconference
- 지휘하실 수 있어요
- 잘 돌아가네
- in the situation room, so...
- Oh, great.
역사의 한 장면에서
영상 통화를 외치다!
My secure video
teleconference with history.
신임 의원 서른세 분만
해치우시면 됩니다
Okay, ma'am, you got
33 senators to get through.
하룻밤에 200 놈 상대하는
포르노 스타가 따로 없군
Oh, boy. Well, I feel like that porn
star who had to do 200 men in one day.
제대로 숨 돌릴
틈도 없겠어, 그치?
At least she got
to lie down, right?
가족 분들도 이리로 오시죠
Well, let's bring
this beautiful family in.
어이쿠 인물들이
아주 판박이시네
Oh, look at this.
You all have good blood.
- 안녕하세요?
- 잘될 수밖에 없는 집안이군
What's up?
I can see it. It's right here.
대통령 님도 안 계신데
시다바리가 왜 왔지?
This isn't a POTUS thing.
Why is scrotus here?
치어리더라고 여기세요
Think of me
as a cheerleader, Mike.
이런, 꽃잎 동동 띄운 욕조에
누워있는 모습을 상상해 버렸어
Oh, God.
I'm imagining you
in a bathtub
full of rose petals.
감사합니다, 살펴 가시고
브라이언 자네 차례일세
Thank you. Off you go.
Brian, you're up.
- 어서, 어서
- 부통령 님
- Come, come.
- Madam Vice President.
- 축하하네
- 영광입니다
- Congratulations.
- What an honor.
반갑기 그지 없구만
It's so good to see you.
영화 일은 잘 돼 가나?
I want to know how all
your filmmaking is going.
- 예?
- 뭐 그런 거 말야
- Beg pardon?
- And so on.
- 무슨 말씀이신지?
- 낚시하잖나
- Beg pardon?
- Your fishing.
물론입니다
월척만을 기다리는 중이죠
Oh, yeah. It's good.
I'm still hunting for that big one.
누군들 안 그렇겠나
대물이라면 사족을 못 쓰지
Well, that's all we want.
We all want the big one, don't we?
- 방금 노리고 말씀하신 거지?
- 넵, 넵
- Did she just make an innuendo?
- Yep. Yep.
엄숙하게 선서하는 바이니
That I will bear true faith...
충성을 다할 것을 맹세합니다
and allegiance to the same.
That I take this obligation
어떠한 심중 유보나
의무의 회피도 없이
freely without any mental
reservation or purpose of evasion
앞으로 최선을 다하여
국회의원으로서의
and that I will well
and faithfully discharge
임무를 성실히 이행하겠습니다
저를 도우소서, 브라이언
the duties of the office of which I
am about to enter, so help me Brian.
아, 제가 브라이언입니다만
- Yes.
- Uh, I am Brian.
- 나도 알지
- '저를 도우소서,하나님'겠죠
- I know.
- I think you mean, "So help you God."
맞아, 그렇지
하나님을 도우소서
Yes, yes.
Oh, so help you God.
- 저를 도우소서, 하나님
- 저를, 하나님이, 됐다
- So help me God.
- Me, God, yes.
살다 보니 이런 일이
식구들을 불러 볼까?
Oh, my God.
Okay, let's get the family in here.
대체 왜 저러실까?
What's going on?
버퍼링 같은 거야
괜찮아지실 거라고
It's just a blip.
She's gonna be fine.
- 루비라고 합니다
- 어머, 루비라고
- I'm Ruby.
- Oh, Ruby.
우리 사촌 오빠
이름으로 딱이겠다
Oh, I wish that was
my cousin's name.
듣다 듣다 이런
인사치레는 또 처음이네
This is the worst small talk
I've ever heard.
저도 진짜 젬병이지만
저보다 더 하시잖아요
And I'm including mine in that
and mine is horrible.
이보다 최악도 있었는걸
She's done worse.
기억도 하기 싫지만
분명 있었지
I can't think of when,
but she has.
살펴 가세요
매리앤?
And off you go.
Maryanne.
뭐 이런 쌍...
What in the living...
...큼한 날이 다 있지
자넬 여기서 만나다니?
Lord of Christ
are you doing here?
- 드디어 입성했군
- 그렇습니다
- But you are.
- I'm here.
새해맞이는 어찌 했나?
So you had a good New Year's?
스키 타러 버몬트로
여행을 갔었죠
Yes, we were skiing in Vermont.
세상사가 그런 거 아니겠나
Well, that's how
the cookie crumbles.
그럼 기념 사진이나 박을까?
Yeah, now let's take a photo.
웨스트윙, 조나입니다
West Wing. Jonah.
필립 도시 의원이 끝이야
금방 마무리 되겠지
Okay, Philip Dorsey's the last
one, so he's gonna be quick.
얼마 전에 부인이랑 사별해서
딸린 식구도 없거든
His wife just died
and he has no family left.
천만다행이다
우리한테 말이야
That's great.
For us, I mean.
- 마칠 테니까 말야
- 응
- 'Cause we're done.
- Okay.
에이미, 때가 됐어
Amy, it's time o'clock.
- 무슨 때?
- 그거 할 때라고
- What's time o'clock?
- Time o'clock.
정말이지...
도저히 못 봐주겠다
This is... I can't
take this anymore.
부인께도 안부 전해 주겠나?
And so won't you give
my love to Patty?
- 사별해서요
- 참, 맞다
- She passed away.
- Yes. Yes.
실례합니다, 부통령 님
때가 왔습니다
Excuse me, ma'am.
It is time o'clock.
좋았어, 어서 선서해야지
All right, let's get
swearing, Philip.
엄숙하게 선서합니다
I do solemnly swear...
국내외의 적들에 대항하여
that I will support and defend
그 어떠한 상황 속에서도
the Constitution
of the United States
미합중국의 헌법 수호에
앞장서겠습니다
against all enemies,
foreign and domestic.
또한 진심으로 맹세...
That I will bear true faith...
- 임신하신 걸까
- 어떡해
- Maybe she's pregnant again.
- Oh, God.
아님 폐경이 왔든가
Or she's menopausal.
또 남성호르몬 제제
달라실 거야, 난 빠질래
Oh, God, she's gonna want that
testosterone gel. I'm out of here.
- 저를 도우소서, 하나님
- ...so help me God.
제발 도와주십쇼
So help me God.
먼저 좀 가 봐야겠네, 필립
Uh, I have to move on, Philip.
홀로 남겨지는 데는
익숙합니다
They all leave me eventually.
- 일 났다, 일 난 거야
- 무슨 일이지?
Something's up. Something's up.
What's going on?
- 부통령 님, 저 쪽입니다
- 아, 그래
- Ma'am. Ma'am. Right here.
- Oh, yeah.
- 부통령 님, 제가...
- 낄 자리가 아냐, 개리
- Ma'am, I've got...
- No, you're not needed here, Gary.
- 대장부들의 거사라고
- 부통령 님, 저는...
- This is man's work.
- Ma'am, should I...
이하동문일세, 댄
Same goes
for you, Dan. No.
- 철저히 봉쇄해야 돼
- 미안, 제군들
- Let's black out till we drop.
- Sorry, fellas.
이만 작별을 고하지
I'll just be closing
this door right now.
잠깐만, 조나였어?
Wait a minute. Jonah's going in?
역사의 한 페이지를
장식하시겠습니다
- Say hi to history, ma'am.
- Oh, God.
저 치들은 종합상황실인데
난 종합썅황실이란 말이지
The men get the situation room,
I get the shituation room?
부통령 님, 원격 접속 중입니다
- Ma'am, the comms should be live now.
- Oh.
다들 안녕하십니까
Hi, gentlemen.
방금 들으신 조크는
어쩌다 보니...
I hope you heard that joke.
우러나와 버렸네요
That was meant
for you to hear it.
부통령 님, 머서 장군입니다
Madam Vice President,
this is General Mercer.
미치고 팔짝 뛰겠네!
3 번 카메라가 암살할걸
This is so awesome.
I'll bet you camera three gets a kill.
장군, 대통령 님
General, Mr. President.
작전명 굿 셰퍼드
문제없이 진행 중입니다
Operation Good Shepherd
is proceeding well, ma'am.
블랙 호크 기에
탑재 된 카메라에서
We are looking at
live feeds from cams
실시간 전송되는 화면입니다
진입 직전입니다
aboard the Black Hawks
and we are about to go in.
- 행운을 빌겠네
- 부통령 님
- Good luck, gentlemen.
- Ma'am.
총격이 시작되면
꽤 시끄러울 겁니다
When the guns go off, they
will be loud, Madam Vice President,
그러니 부디 욕설은
거두어 주시길
so no swearing.
조지, 그러한 언사야말로
대단히 부적절하네만
George, comments like that
are incredibly inappropriate
여러 국민의 목숨이
위태로운 이 판국에
when people's lives
are at stake.
리필이나 해 와야겠다
I've got to
get a refill here.
우리 점보가 텅텅 비었네
좀 지나갑시다
Old jumbo needs a refill.
Excuse me.
- 사진 잘 받으시네요
- 조나, 지금 아주
- It's a good photo, ma'am.
- Jonah, there are more important things
중대한 기로에 서 있다고
going on in the world
right now.
오, 그래 ㅎ
Oh, yeah.
Huh.
구매 승인 완료
Acquisition is confirmed.
계란들을 장바구니에 담았다!
The eggs are back
in the basket!
옳지! 계라싸비야!
Yeah!
Eggs-shak-a-laka!
망할 면상들 쳐발라 주겠어
In your fucking face, eggs.
뭡니까? 인질들 모두
구조해 냈답니까?
What? The hostages?
We got 'em?
Yeah!
혁혁한 공이십니다!
Legacy marker.
Yeah!
개리, 개리
Gary. Gary.
수의 재출석 건은
뉴스란에서 밀리겠군요
So Sue's return to the hearing's
wiped off the news map.
그거 신경 쓸 겨를이 어딨대?
That's the last thing on
anyone's mind today. Come on.
물론입죠
Of course.
작년 사무용품 구입비용은
Last year's expenditure
on office supplies
전년도 대비 정확히
동일한 수준입니다
was held at the exact same level
as the previous year.
그러니까 합계를 내자면...
Which means
that the total sum...
더 이상 뽑아 먹을
뉴스 거리가 없나 봅니다
Seems like you're
no longer news, Miss Wilson.
할당된 15 분이 끝났습니다
Your 15 minutes might be up.
공수래공수거 아니겠습니까
Ashes to ashes,
엄중함에는 자중이 약이죠
robust to dust.
수, 2 탄은 어땠어?
Oh, hey, Sue.
How was the sequel?
간략했죠
Short.
바람 들었다가 버림받는 거죠
스타병이 무서워요
Pumped and dumped
by the fame monster, huh?
안전 보장 회의에서
임무 수행 평가서 받아 왔어
Oh, I got the full mission
eval from the NSC.
- 부통령 님 뵙자고
- 들어가자
- Let's speak to the veep.
- Let's go.
네?
Yep?
- 부통령 님
- 감축 드립니다
- Ma'am.
- Congratulations, ma'am.
이런 고마울 데가, 라이언 군
Thank you, Mr. Ryan.
작전명 굿 셰퍼드
훌륭히 완수하셨습니다
Operation Good Shepherd...
total success.
오예! 존나 해병대 필수다
Yeah!
Semper fucking fee.
- 승이요
- 그래, 필승
- Fi.
- Fi. Fi, right.
인질 모두 무사 귀환했습니다
All hostages
recovered unharmed.
- 부상자는 한 명이고요
- 자세하게 어떤?
- Only one injury.
- Detail on that injury?
제 2 정찰 부대 소속
병장이군요
A Marine sergeant,
2nd recon battalion,
포탄 파편에
다리를 잃었습니다
stray ordnance, he lost a leg.
음, 잠깐만
Uh... wait, wait.
우리 측 해병 말인가?
You mean one of our
Marines lost a leg?
맞습니다
왼 다리라는군요
Yes, ma'am.
His left leg, ma'am.
음...
Um...
완전히 다?
the entire leg?
무릎 위부터
절단한 걸로 압니다
I believe he lost
from above the knee.
아, 그렇담...
Oh, so they were able to...
발은 보전할 수가?
just salvage his foot?
아뇨, 애초에 부상 범위가...
No, I believe he lost
from above...
무릎 아래로는 살릴 수가
없었을 겁니다
he basically doesn't have a
leg from above the knee down.
작전에 참여했던 친구인가?
Was he part of the operation?
실은 8 일에 본국 귀환할
예정인 병사였습니다
Yes. He was actually due to
be rotated out on the eighth.
아, 8 일
Oh, on the eighth.
하, 그렇구나
Huh. Okay.
지금 상태는...
Is he...
고통이 심하다 하는가?
ahem, is he in a lot of pain?
- 아, 아닙니다
- 다행이군
- Oh, no, ma'am.
- Oh, good.
약물 유도 혼수 상태입니다
No, he's in an induced coma.
그렇지만 의식을 차리면...
But I suppose
when he wakes up...
바람 좀 쐬고 오겠네
I just need to get some air.
Excuse me.
- 다시 한 번 축하드립니다
- 아아주 고맙네
- Congratulations again, ma'am.
- Thanks a million.
- 축하합니다, 부통령 님
- 고마워
- Congratulations, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- 한 병사가 다릴 잃었어
- 이리 기쁠 데가요, 이리도
- I lost a man his leg, Mike.
- So good. So good.
아니, 그게 아니라
나 때문에 다리를 잃었다고
No, no, no.
I lost a man his leg, Mike.
고맙습니다
고마워요, 모두들
Thanks.
Thanks, guys.
감사합니다
Thank you.
아주 그냥
본 때를 보여주셨습니다
Ma'am, I just want to say
consummate performance.
인질들도 무사히
구조했을 뿐더러
Not only did you rescue
the hostages,
수도 찍소리 못하게
밟으셨잖습니까
but you annihilated Sue.
수가 관심에서 멀어지기에
더없이 좋은 날이었습니다
You picked the operation date to
blow her appearance off the map.
신의 한 수였습니다
천재적이셔요
I mean, genius play, ma'am.
Genius.
진격의 저승사자라는
별명 어떠십니까
I call that overshadowboxing.
내 말 잘 들어, 댄
You know what, Dan?
다른 사람 귓구멍에다 대고
끝도 없이 소곤거리면 말야
The problem with being so close
to somebody's ear all the time
그 사람 머릿속까지
읽을 수 있다고 착각이 들지
is that you begin to think that
you can see inside their head,
근데 그럴 순 없거든
그럴 수 없다고
but you can't, Dan.
You can't.
- 내 말 이해했나?
- 이해했습니다
- Do you understand that?
- Understood, ma'am.
- 저기, 부통령 님
- 응?
- Hey, ma'am.
- Yes?
시나몬 모카 같은 거
타 드릴까요?
Can I get you a cinnamon mocha
or something?
네, 금방 갖다 드릴게요
Yeah, let me get that for you.
종말을 고하게, 이 친구야
End of an era, buddy.
종말을
End of an era.
내가 그렇게 만든 거야
I lost a man his leg.
그만 하세요, 부통령 님
Please stop saying that, ma'am.
금세 기력을 되찾을 겁니다
촉이 온다고요
He'll bounce back.
I got a feeling.
부통령직이란 게 본래
대의를 위해
Ma'am, the vice president
sometimes has to do
소의를 접을 수밖에
없을 때가 오잖아요
bad things to make
good things happen.
부통령 님의 큰 뜻을
이루던 와중에 발생한
The leg is just
the price of admission
불의의 사고였을 뿐예요
to the place you wanted to be.
그 해병을 백악관에
초청하는 건 어떨까
Well, maybe we could
invite him to the White House.
회복이 좀 됐을 즈음에...
You know, once he's
back up on his...
좋죠, 휠체어 전용로를
설치하면 되니까요
Sure, we'll roll out the ramps.
부통령 님, 요즘 의족이
아주 감쪽같이 잘 나온답니다
Ma'am, some of the prosthetic
legs they have these days
are as good as real legs.
바스러져 가는 제 다리
두 짝보다 더 좋을걸요
I guarantee you they're
better than my shitty legs.
다리라면 지긋지긋해요
제게 만약 기회가 주어...
I hate my legs.
In fact, if I had the choice...
응?
Huh?
아닙니다
가 보겠습니다
Never mind.
I'm gonna go.
부통령 님, 달달한 아몬드
크로아상은 어떠실는지요?
Hey, ma'am.
How would you like
a nice little almond croissant?
아, 좋지
정말 행복하겠어
Oh, yeah.
I would love that.
좋습니다, 좋아요
Okay. Okay.
큰 걸로 준비해 주겠어?
Can you make it a big one
그 안에 몰래 숨어들어서는
so you can stuff me
inside of it
통으로 밀수출 될 수 있게
and smuggle me out of here?
당연히 해 드릴 수 있죠
Of course I can.
속에는 자그마한 우리 라즈베리
친구들이 기다리고 있을 거예요
And there might be a little
raspberry surprise in them.
그렇구나
고마워
Okay.
Thank you.
별 말씀을요
My pleasure.
한글자막 D (13myowncut@gmail.com)